# **Matthew Topping**

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/matthew-topping-82612a40/ Full UK driving license (Clean)

### **Personal Statement**

A system administrator with over twelve years' experience in the NHS, excited to be looking for a new challenge after completing a Bachelor of Engineering degree. All projects undertaken are committed to fully and enthusiastically. A self-starter ready to put skills into practice in a forward thinking organisation. Consistently striving to improve efficiency and looking for opportunities to use initiative. A driven individual motivated by learning new competencies to aid in the consultation and delivery of projects.

# **Key Skills**

- Excellent communication skills, both written and verbal, with colleagues, clients and any sub-contractors that may be working within the department.
- Being a proactive and efficient, self-directed learner.
- Scheduling mandatory training to maintain personal course record in line with organisational policies.
- Managing and prioritising own workload to meet deadlines.
- Improving quality with high attention to detail, with particular emphasis on Trust Information Governance policies which limit what data is collected and how it can be used.
- A flexible approach to working covering periods of maternity, sickness and annual leave. Dealing with ad hoc queries and re-prioritise workload accordingly.
- Proficiency in the use of SAP Crystal Reports, SQL and Active Directory management.

## **Education**

#### The Open University (September 2011 – September 2020)

Bachelor of Engineering (Honours), Upper Second-class Honours (2.1). Energy and sustainability pathway. An Institution of Engineering and Technology (IET) accredited programme. Fulfils the current requirements for the Engineering Council's initial educational standards for Chartered Engineer. Learning outcomes closely aligned with the UK Standard for Professional Engineering Competence.

### **University of Sunderland** (September 2014 – June 2015)

Postgraduate certificate in Health Information Management. Topics included process improvement for health information systems, application development and statistical representation.

### University of Teesside (September 2000 – June 2004)

Studying BSc Computer Science; awarded a Diploma in Higher Education. Course content included programming languages, website design and database creation and administration.

# **Employment History**

### Medical Image Management System (MIMS) Administrator (November 2019 – Present)

Medical Photography, South Tees Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust

- Provide a comprehensive image management service in support of clinical assessment.
- Upload images on to MIMS ensuring access restricted for permitted use according to the level of consent indicated by the patient.
- Provide MIMS access to appropriate authorised clinicians by maintaining user accounts and system rights to ensure data quality and data protection.
- Inputting and manipulation of data in order to maintain system integrity and accurate records.
- Analyse and troubleshoot a range of IT issues and escalate as necessary.
- Act as first line support for MIMS system users Trust wide which involves fault finding, problem solving and checking configuration settings.
- Deliver training for MIMS and image upload to department and Trust wide staff.
- Monitor user activity to ensure compliance with Data Protection and Information Governance, reporting any risks or issues that arise.
- Liaise with police, social services and child/adult protection services for the preparation of images for legal cases.
- Meet with software providers to arrange upgrades and discuss future system developments.

## Imaging Support Worker (March 2013 – November 2019)

Medical Photography, South Tees Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust

- Completed Health Information Management course in 2014/15 to progress my role from department assistant to imaging support worker.
- The first point of contact for patients, booking in jobs and transferring them to photographers.
- Managing calls and directing enquiries to the appropriate member of staff.
- · Receiving and distributing all department mail.
- Provide holiday and sickness cover to the system administrator.
- Quality checking jobs to ensure data validity and identifying how errors can be resolved.
- Ensuring all data collected by the department is managed appropriately and disposed of in line with UK GDPR on retention periods.
- Producing monthly activity reports for management.
- Maintaining stock levels by ordering and receiving deliveries.
- · Participation in audit activities and reporting.
- Also assumed the role of fire officer for the entire office staff.

### Data Input Clerk (September 2008 – March 2013)

Rehabilitation Centre, South Tees Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust

- Data entry of therapist contact sheets into hospital system accurately and timely.
- Managing incoming phone calls and mail.

#### **Employment Gap Summary** (February 2006 – September 2008)

• Voluntary work with gardener. Volunteer at the Wildlife Trust. Plastering course. Bricklaying course.

### **Hobbies & Interests**

I enjoy keeping fit by cycling, swimming and running with the aim of taking part in a triathlon. I am a member of a virtual airline, an online community that replicates real-world flights using various flight simulators. I recently played guitar in a band which I hope to continue again now my studies are complete. In order to continue learning new skills, I enjoy programming using Python and creating visual projects using Blender.